Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MS/M.Sc(Science) [computer Science

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

and Engineering]



Software Engineer seeking roles in Data Science, Software
Development,DeepLearning, Gathering,Solution Designing,Software Coding,Gap
Analysis,Performance Tuning,Machine Learning,Algorithms,C,Data
Structures,C++,MATLAB



Current Designation: NA

Current Company: NA

Current Location: Delhi

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: information retrieval, NLP, Machine Learning, Algorithms, C, Data

Structures, Programming, C++, c++, MATLAB, Deep Learning, Neural Networks, tensorflow, Python, Artificial Intelligence, Data

Science, Data Mining, Natural Language Processing, Maths, Text Mining

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

### **Summary**

A focused professional with MS(By Research) from IIT Kanpur offering 3 + years of experience in Software Engineering,IT Project Management,Requirement Gathering,Solution Designing,Coding,Incident Management,Change Management,Gap Analysis,Performance Tuning,Algorithms,C,Data Structures,C++,MATLAB,Core Java,HTML and is looking for a career in Machine Learning/Deep Learning

# **Work Experience**

NA as NA

Nov 2020 to Till Date

ClearTax as Software Engineer

Aug 2020 to Nov 2020

Developed an E-Invoicing API in python to generate B2C QR code

#### Bharat Electronics Limited- Central Research Laboratory as Project Engineer

Mar 2015 to Dec 2017

Command and Control System Phase-V (IACCS-V) project

Developed CRS Flight Plan algorithms that were used to detect collision of flights in C++ language

Used Data Distribution Services technology to interact with other modules like Threat Evaluation, Recovery, Web, Database etc.

Modelled WA backend algorithms in MATLAB that assign weapons to neutralize the targets

Developed Simulator for CRS, WA and DSS in Qt

Documented System & Software Requirements, Software Architecture and Testing documents in IBM Doors & IBM Raphsody application

https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=d76001a7b2311634f4e86f199bf0b0215c0f585648145d180b1741515d5c591f405c42...

**Tectura Infotech Pvt. Ltd.** as Associate Software Developer Jul 2013 to Dec 2013

### **Education**

1/22/2021

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from Jaypee University of Engineering and Technology, guna in 2013

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (computer Science and Engineering) from Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur in 2020

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Machine Learning

Algorithms

Deep Learning

### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
C, C++		0 Month(s)
MACHINE LEARNING		0 Month(s)
Deep learning		0 Month(s)
Data Science		
MATLAB		
Data Structures		
core java, html		
Windows XP, Vista, 7, 8.1, 10		
Red Hat Enterprise Linux		

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			

### **Affirmative Action**

Job Type: Permanent

Category: General
Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

**Work Authorization**